Amar Gudipalle

Data Scientist

Phone

Email

Address Hyderabad TG 500078

7013744807 & 9490042886

Amargudipalle@gmail.com

Github Link https://github.com/Amargudipalle/Data-Science-Projects

www.linkedin.com/in/amar-gudipalle-752891192

Professional Summary

Data Scientist with strong math background and **1.3 + years** of experience using predictive modelling, data processing, and data mining algorithms to solve challenging business problems. Involved in Python open source community and passionate about deep reinforcement learning.

LinkedIn

Work History

AI Engineer

Gnani.ai Bangalore Karnataka

- Work on developing Algorithms in Multilingual Speech Recognition, Entity detections, and automated conversations. Work on developing NLP framework an all.
- Develop and take to production on critical real-world scenarios like Wake-up word detection,
 Noisy channel ASR performance, Multi speaker detection. Solving real-world scenarios for user commands and requests, and build scalable systems that solve their problems

Data Analyst

Design Nation Hyderabad Telangana

- Collecting and interpreting data after that Analysing the results
- Reporting the results back to the relevant members of the business
- Identifying patterns and trends in data sets
- Working alongside teams within the business or the management team to establish business needs. Defining new data collection and analysis processes
- Coordinated statistical data analysis, design, and information flow.

AI Engineer Intern

Think Quick Hyderabad Telangana

- Created plans and communicated deadlines to ensure projects were completed on time.
- Responsibilities include transforming natural language data into useful features using NLP techniques to feed classification, information extraction algorithms.

Data Engineering Trainee

2020-11 - 2020-12

MedTourEasy Hyderabad Telangana

- Understanding healthcare-specific EMR data models, catalogue data dictionaries, and map data elements to standard data specifications.
- Worked closely with technology teams to understand processes and policies driving the team goals.
- Document and improving data mapping and data element identification processes across the entire data ingestion team.

Data Engineer Intern

2020-10 - 2020-11

The Sparks Foundation Hyderabad Telangana

- Work on Data Architecture and Collect the Data
- Conducting Research then Improve the skills and generate valuable business insights
- Create models and identify patterns then Automate the Task

Projects Worked On

- Web Scraping (Python): Extracting the performance 10K race that took place in Hillsboro, OR
 on June 2019 from Huber timing website, making analysis of data and performing certain
 visualization's on data.
- **Heart Disease Prediction using Machine Learning**: Used Machine Learning models to predict whether any person is suffering from heart disease or not.
- Implement a DNA Classifier using NLP: Classified a model that can predict a gene's function based on the DNA sequence.
- On Deep Learning: Based on the chest X-rays. Classified model that can predict an image and say that the person is having disease or not.

Software Skills

- NLP and Deep Learning: Text mining, FNN, CNN, RNN with Tensor Flow, Keras and Pytorch.
- Machine Learning:-Linear regression, Logistic, Naive Bayes, and Decision tree, Random Forest, KNN, K-means clustering, Time Series and SVM
- Databases :- SQL
- Technical Skills: Python, Numpy, Pandas, Data Visualization, Web scraping.
- Software Skill:- Clanguage, HTML, CSS, MATLAB

Final Year Mini Project

- Title: Performance Analysis of OFDM using 4PSK, 8PSK and 16PSK.
- **Description:** The main aim is the performance of 4 PSK is better than both 8 PSK and 16 PSK because the BER values with respect to the Eb/No (in dB) in case of 4 PSK are lower than the values obtained in the case of 8 PSK and 16 PSK.

Final Year Major Project

- Title: Detection of blood vessels using retinal fundus images using MATLAB.
- **Description:** The main objective behind this project is the algorithm of detection of optic disk, blood vessels and exudates are investigated using the software called MATLAB.

Education

Bachelor of Technology: Electronics and Communication Engineering 2013-04 - 2017-05

Vardhaman College of Engineering Hyderabad

Intermediate: MPC 2010-03 - 2013-04

Narayana Junior College Hyderabad

64 % Percentage

SSC: CBSE 2009-04 - 2010-05

Army School Hyderabad

6.8 CGPA

Declaration

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.